Guide to Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Edward H. Litchfield, Administrative Files, 1956-1965 UA.2.10.1956-1965
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Edward H. Litchfield, Administrative Files
1956-1965
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Chancellor
UA.2.10.1956-1965
65 Linear Feet (155 boxes)
CONTENT WARNING -- This finding aid contains records that have been identified as including offensive, harmful, racist, or misrepresentative creator supplied language. In keeping with archival best practice, this language has been retained to preserve the context of the records. In keeping but acknowledging this language, A&SC hopes to encourage critical assessment and questioning of historical materials. Researchers should bear this in mind when accessing. Edward H. Litchfield, formerly the Dean of the School of Business and Public Administration at Cornell University, assumed the role of Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh on July 1, 1956. This collection contains a large amount of material dealing with all aspects of Litchfield's administration including his resignation on July 1, 1965.
Biography
Edward H. Litchfield, formerly the Dean of the School of Business and Public Administration at Cornell University, assumed the role of Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh on July 1, 1956. In addition to his new position as Chancellor, Litchfield maintained several connections to the business world, including committee memberships and directorships with corporations such as Smith-Corona, Avco, and Studebaker-Packard.
Litchfield orchestrated many changes at the University of Pittsburgh such as a reorganization of the administrative structure, salary increases for employees, and pension increases for retired professors. He focused many of his early activities on improving faculty conditions, reducing teaching loads, and implementing sabbatical leaves and the formation of the Senate Council. A second focus was on improving and developing the academic programs by limiting entrance to professional schools to graduate students and by improving the quality of the professors.
One of Litchfield's most important contributions was physically expanding the campus through the addition of dormitories, the purchase of the Schenley Hotel and the acquisition or construction of several additional buildings. Financial problems, due to overspending and unforeseen problems, characterized the later part of Litchfield's chancellorship, until his resignation in July, 1965.
He, along with his wife, his two youngest children, and his mother, were killed in a private airplane crash on March 8, 1968 over Lake Michigan near Meigs Field. The Litchfield Towers (dormitories) on Pitt's main campus were named in his honor.
Related Material
The Archives Service Center also holds the personal papers of Edward H. Litchfield.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains a large amount of material dealing with all aspects of Litchfield's administration. The material dates from 1956 to 1965, his term in the office. It contains a number of different items, but primarily correspondence.
The material is arranged into two series, the first of which is arranged alphabetically by topic and chronologically within the topic. The second series contains material identified by the Chancellor as being of archival value. These items are arranged, broadly, by topical categories.
Access Restrictions
Folder 1317 in Box 156 is restricted because it contains personnel files.
Acquisition Information
The collection was transferred to the University Archives in 1965.
Previous Citation
Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Edward H. Litchfield, Administrative Files, 1956-1965, UA.2.10.1956-1965, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
University of Pittsburgh; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Records and correspondence; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Administration; Correspondence; Administrative records; University of Pittsburgh. Chancellor -- Records and correspondence; University of Pittsburgh -- Administration; Litchfield, Edward H. (Edward Harold)
- Subject List, 1956-1965; I.
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, January-November 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, December 1959 - December 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, January-December 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, January-December 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9, 12)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, January-December 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10-11, 13)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, Brochure:"Development Plans and Projects for the Academic Disciplines"; Correspondence regarding "The Role of Academic Disciplines in a Modern University" (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, Correspondence regarding Mr. Wolf Mankowitz (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, January-December 1964 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, January-May 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Academic Disciplines, Vice Chancellor, Disciplines Search Committee (Biographical Data on the Candidates) (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
  - Academic Regalia (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Academic Administrative Planning Director J. R. Dillon - Lab fees, Tuition Rates, Admissions, Equipment, House Bill (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Auxiliary Enterprises Dr. Keith S. Snyder, J. C. Langstaff (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Allegheny Observatory (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Allegheny Seminar, Conference Booklets, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Anniversary 175th (Box 4, Folder 27-31)
    Scope and Contents note
    These files 27-31 contain: Newspaper Clippings, Programs, Events, Honorary Degrees, Thank you letters, and Programming. The files also include: Guest Lists, Nationality Committee Program, Symposia and Invitations to Associations, Colleges and Universities, Foundations, Local Schools, and Miscellaneous.
  - Appalachia Physical Education Development; Report of the Appalachian Institute Committee (Washington,); Community Response to the Loss of Industry - A Study by the University of Virginia, October 1964 July 13, 1964. (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), 1960-1963, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 33-35)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), Ecuador (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), Faculty Committee on Faculty Standards, Stanton Crawford-Dean of the Faculties, Leland P. Deck-Director of Personnel (Box 5, Folder 37-38)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), Faculty Committee on Faculty Development (Box 5, Folder 39-40)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), Forbes Field Controversy (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), Nigeria - Graduate School of Public and International Affairs (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), Nigeria - Graduate School of Public and International Affairs (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), Speech to Realtors - University and the Economy (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), University Study Committee (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Assistants to the Chancellor (material from Robert H. Bailie), Water Pollution Center (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Inaugural Seminar Papers MISSING FOLDER (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Athletics, Director of, Frank Carver, Stadium - use as Municipal stadium and for Steelers, 1956-1959 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Athletics, Director of, Frank Carver, Carroll Cook (Beano), Bribes of Basketball Players, 1960-1965 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Athletics, Director of, University Committee on Athletics, Micholsen Issue (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Athletics, Director of, Black Players Issue, Sugar Bowl Incident (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - A General
    - Adams - American Association for Health (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - American Association of University - Arbuthnot (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Archives - Art (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Association - Australian (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Babcock Room, Reservations and Dedication (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Biological Sciences, Department of (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Board of Trustees
    - Athletic Committee (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Audit Committee (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Budget and Audit Committee, March - November 1964, December 1964 - January 1965, February-May 1965 (Box 7, Folder 60-62)
    - By-laws Committee (Box 8, Folder 63-64)
    - Educational Policies Committee (Box 8, Folder 65-66)
    - Executive Committee, August 1957 -March 1960, June 1960-January 1961 (Box 8, Folder 67-68)
    - Executive Committee, Athletics/Physical Education; Joint Meeting of Executive and Finance Committee, June 13,1961 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Executive Committee, Meeting at Rolling Rock,; Financial Statements and Spending,;Meeting, January - February 1961 January 1961 March-April 1961 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Executive Committee, Faculty Housing,; Attendance and Mail Ballots, August 1961 April - July 1962 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Executive Committee, Agenda- Meeting, August 14, 1961, September 12, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 72-73)
    - Executive Committee, Joint Meeting of Executive and Finance Committees, November 14, 1961, December 11, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 74-75)
    - Executive Committee, Endowments/Finance, Trust Department, March -April 1962 (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Executive Committee, Review of Investments, March -April 1962 (Box 9, Folder 77)
    - Executive Committee, Memos from Stanton C. Crawford, Secretary, September 1961- September 1962 (Box 9, Folder 78)
    - Executive Committee, September-November 1962, January- September 1963 (Box 9, Folder 79-80)
    - Executive Committee, Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, Agenda-Meeting, November 4, 1963, December 10, 1963, February-July 1964, July 1964-July 1965 (Box 10, Folder 81-84)
    - Faculty Participation in Policy Making Report on Organizational Relationships in Certain Universities (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Board of Trustees,Faculty Participation in Policy Making, 1957, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 86-87)
    - Finance Committee, August 1962-July 1965 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Finance Committee, August 1960-July 1962, August 1959-July 1960 (Box 12, Folder 89-90)
    - Finance Committee, June 1955-July 1959 (Box 13, Folder 91)
    - General Trustees Meetings, April-June 1965, January-February 1965, October 1964 (Box 13, Folder 92-94)
    - Finance Committee, October 27, 1964, October 27, 1964, January-May 1964, January 14,1964 (Box 14, Folder 95-98)
    - General Trustees Meetings, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 99-102)
    - Meetings, 1961-1963 (Box 15, Folder 103-110)
    - Meetings, 1960-1961 (Box 16, Folder 111-118)
    - Meetings, 1955-1959 (Box 17, Folder 119-124)
    - Honorary Degrees Committee, 1960-1964, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 125-126)
    - Correspondence for each Trustee
      - A - H (Box 18, Folder 127-129)
      - La - Lo (Box 18, Folder 130-131)
      - M - Pe (Box 19, Folder 132-133)
      - Gwilym A. Price (Box 19, Folder 134)
      - R (Box 19, Folder 135)
      - Alan M. Scaife (Box 19, Folder 136-137)
      - Alan M. Scaife (Box 20, Folder 138-140)
      - Sch-Y (Box 20, Folder 141-142)
    - Nominating Committee (Box 20, Folder 143)
    - Physical Plant and Site Development Committee (Box 20, Folder 144)
    - Planning and Development Committee, General (Box 20, Folder 145)
    - Planning and Development Committee, Bowman, Dr. John G. - Dedication of Cathedral of Learning to him, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 146)
    - Planning and Development Committee, Bradford Campus (Box 21, Folder 147)
    - Planning and Development Committee, British Commonwealth Universities to visit Pitt (Box 21, Folder 148)
    - Planning and Development Committee, Budget Committee of the University, Budget Cutting, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 149-152)
  - Book Center (Box 21, Folder 153)
  - Buhl Foundation (Box 22, Folder 154)
  - Bureau of Business Research, 1956-1961 (Box 22, Folder 155-156)
  - Business, Graduate School of, 1956-1965 (Box 22, Folder 157-160)
  - Business Administration, School of Special Search Committee, School of Special Search Committee (Box 22, Folder 161)
  - Business Administration, School of Special Search Committee, School of Special Board Visitors (Box 23, Folder 162)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, 1963-1965 (Box 23, Folder 163-171)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, 1961-1963 (Box 24, Folder 172-178)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, 1957-1961 (Box 25, Folder 179-187)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, 1956-1957 (Box 26, Folder 188-192)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, Masonic Property, Clyde Street Property (Box 26, Folder 193)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, Long Term Financing, 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 194-195)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, Brennan, Joseph (Box 26, Folder 196)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, Gift Lend Back Plan (Box 27, Folder 197)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, Taxation on Chancellor's Residence (Box 27, Folder 198)
  - Business Affairs, Vice Chancellor, Fifth - Craig Properties (Box 27, Folder 199)
  - B General
    - Barnes - Blatt (Box 27, Folder 200)
    - Bowman - Bruce (Box 27, Folder 201)
    - Buchanan - Burgh (Box 27, Folder 202)
    - Burkavage - Byrom (Box 27, Folder 203)
  - Calendar Committee (Box 27, Folder 204)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology, 1960-1965 (Box 27, Folder 205)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology, 1955-1960 (Box 27, Folder 206)
  - Catalog, University - Committee to Revise (Box 27, Folder 207)
  - Center for the Advancement of Education (Box 28, Folder 208)
  - Center for the Philosophy of Science (Box 28, Folder 209)
  - Center for Regional Economic Studies (Box 28, Folder 210)
  - Chamber Music Society (Box 28, Folder 211)
  - Chancellor's Office Survey (Staff and their Duties) (Box 28, Folder 212)
  - Chancellor's Staff, Administrative Committee, May 1956-November 1957 (Box 28, Folder 213)
  - Chancellor's Staff, Administrative Committee Organizational Manual (Box 28, Folder 214)
  - Chancellor's Staff, Memoranda to Members, August 1963 April 1965 (Box 28, Folder 215)
  - Chancellor's Staff, Memoranda to Members, May 1962-June 1963 (Box 28, Folder 216)
  - Chancellor's Staff, Memoranda to Members, April 1958-April 1962 (Box 28, Folder 217-221)
  - Chancellor's Staff, Off-Campus Meetings: Tumble Run, November 2, 1961-May 1965 (Box 29, Folder 222-226)
  - Chancellor's Staff, Off-Campus Meetings: Rolling Rock, August 1959-January 1964 (Box 29, Folder 227-229)
  - Chancellor's Staff, Chancellor's Staff, Off-Campus Meetings:, June 9 - 12, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 230)
  - Chancellor's Staff, Off-Campus Meetings: Morgantown (Lakeview Club), January 14-16, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 231)
  - Chaplain (Box 30, Folder 232)
  - Chatham College (Box 30, Folder 233)
  - Chauffeur (Box 30, Folder 234)
  - Chemistry, Department of (Box 30, Folder 235)
  - Chile, December 1961-April 1964 (Box 30, Folder 236-237)
  - China (Box 30, Folder 238)
  - Christmas Program, 1959-1963 (Box 31, Folder 240-241)
  - Citizenship Clearing House, November 1955-September 1959 (Box 31, Folder 242-245)
  - City Council (Box 31, Folder 246)
  - City Planning Commission Luncheon, September 1958 (Box 31, Folder 247)
  - City Planning Department, 1962-1964 (Box 31, Folder 248)
  - City Planning Department,"Critical Review of Forms, Features, and Feasibilities of the Prodigious City" by Patrick Horsbrugh,(308 Pages), 1963 (Box 31, Folder 249)
  - Classics Department (Box 32, Folder 250)
  - Clinical Science, Department of (Box 32, Folder 251)
  - Clipping: "Kennedy Gets Report On Industry Exposition,"(Litchfield in Picture), May 10, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 252)
  - College Entrance Examination Board (Box 32, Folder 253)
  - Colodny Case (Concern about Communism), 1961 (Box 32, Folder 254-255)
  - Colombia, Bogota, 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 256)
  - Colombia, Bogota, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 257)
  - Commission on Civil Rights, Civil Rights Act of, February-November 1959, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 258)
  - Commission on Civil Rights, September 1958-January 1959 (Box 32, Folder 259)
  - Community Colleges (Box 32, Folder 260)
  - Comptroller, 1955-1965 (Box 33, Folder 261-262)
  - Computation and Data Processing Center, 1956-1964 (Box 33, Folder 263-264)
  - Computation and Data Processing Center,Information Retrieval; University Computing Facilities (Box 33, Folder 265)
  - Council on Computer Science (Box 33, Folder 266)
  - Condolence Letters (Box 33, Folder 267)
  - Congress (Box 33, Folder 268)
  - Continuing Professional Education, University Professor for (Box 33, Folder 269)
  - Coordinated Education Center, 1959-1963 (Box 33, Folder 270-271)
  - Coordinated Education Center, Regional Interrelationships of Secondary Schools, Colleges, and Professional Schools, June 1958-September 1959 (Box 34, Folder 272)
  - Coordinated Education Center, November 1957-June 1958 (Box 34, Folder 273)
  - Coordinated Education Center, Science of Learning Council (Box 34, Folder 274)
  - Costa Rica (Box 34, Folder 275)
  - Council of Deans, October 1955-June 1959 (Box 34, Folder 276-280)
  - Council of Deans, July 1959-November 1961 (Box 35, Folder 281-284)
  - Council of Deans, Mountain View Meeting, December 8 - 9, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 285)
  - Council of Deans, January - August 1962 (Box 35, Folder 286)
  - Council of Deans, September 1962-November 1963 (Box 36, Folder 287-290)
  - Council for Financial Aid to Education, July 1955 - August 1964 (Box 37, Folder 291-292)
  - Crawford, Stanton C., Acting Chancellor (Litchfield Resignation) (Box 37, Folder 293)
  - Crawford, Stanton C., Acting Chancellor Security information, Handling of Classified Matter, Government Research (Box 37, Folder 294)
  - Cresap Report (Box 37, Folder 295)
  - Croghan - Schenley Room (Box 37, Folder 296)
  - Cultural and Educational Exchange, 1958 - 1963 (Box 37, Folder 297-300)
  - Cultural and Educational Exchange, 1956 - 1957 (Box 38, Folder 301-302)
  - Cultural and Educational Exchange,Regional Conference, February 20, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 303)
  - Cultural and Educational Exchange,Regional Conference, - Replies, February 20, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 304)
  - C General
    - Cable - Cambria (Box 38, Folder 305)
    - Campbell - Carbundum (Box 38, Folder 306)
    - Carlson - Carroll (Box 38, Folder 307)
    - Carson - Cerf (Box 39, Folder 308)
    - Chalmers - Chester (Box 39, Folder 309)
    - Chicago - Child (Box 39, Folder 310)
    - Childs - Citizens Advisory (Box 39, Folder 311)
    - Citizens Committee - City (Box 39, Folder 312)
    - Civic - Collazo (Box 39, Folder 313)
    - College - Colwell (Box 39, Folder 314)
    - Commerce - Committee (Box 40, Folder 315)
    - Common - Conrad (Box 40, Folder 316)
    - Consad - Coulter (Box 40, Folder 317)
    - Council - Crissman (Box 40, Folder 318)
    - Critchfield - Czudnowski (Box 40, Folder 319)
  - Dean of Men (Box 40, Folder 320)
  - Dean of Students (Box 40, Folder 321)
  - Dean of Women (and Dean of Students) Helen Rush (Box 40, Folder 322)
  - Deans - University of Pittsburgh (Box 40, Folder 323)
  - Dentistry, School of, April 1961-July 1965 (Box 40, Folder 324-325)
  - Dentistry, School of, June 1956 - March 1961 (Box 41, Folder 326)
  - Development, Assistant Chancellor, December 1959-July 1965 (Box 41, Folder 327-329)
  - Development, Assistant Chancellor, Report of Gifts and Grants, January-August 1964 (Box 41, Folder 330)
  - Development, Assistant Chancellor, Report of Gifts and Grants, September 1964-May 1965 (Box 41, Folder 331)
  - Development, Assistant Chancellor, Phillip H. Powers; Edgar Cale, 1961-1963 (Box 41, Folder 332)
  - Development, Assistant Chancellor, Director of, October 1958-November 1964 (Box 42, Folder 333)
  - Development, Century Club and Scholarship Funds (Box 42, Folder 334)
  - Development, University of Pittsburgh (Box 42, Folder 335)
  - Disciplines Faculty, Member of (Box 42, Folder 336)
  - Discrimination (Box 42, Folder 337)
  - Dormitories (Box 42, Folder 338)
  - D General
    - Dahl - Davidson (Box 42, Folder 339)
    - Davis - Delaware (Box 42, Folder 340)
    - Dellmuth - Dent (Box 42, Folder 341)
    - Denton - Dimmick (Box 42, Folder 342)
    - Directors - Downie (Box 43, Folder 343)
    - Drake - Drumm (Box 43, Folder 344)
    - Drummond - Dykstra (Box 43, Folder 345)
  - Earth and Planetary Sciences, Department of (Box 43, Folder 346)
  - Economics, Department of (Box 43, Folder 347)
  - Ecuador, General (Box 43, Folder 348)
  - Ecuador, January 196-June 1965 (Box 43, Folder 349-357)
  - Ecuador, Schaeffer Reports, Shortwave Broadcasts (Box 43, Folder 358)
  - Education, School of, Tri-State Area School Study Council (Box 45, Folder 359)
  - Education, School of, March 1956-December 1964 (Box 45, Folder 360-366)
  - Education, School of, Advisory Committee on Teacher Education (Box 46, Folder 367)
  - Educational Continuum (Box 46, Folder 368)
  - Educational Exchange, May 1956-June 1957 (Box 46, Folder 369-370)
  - Educational Planning (Box 46, Folder 371)
  - Educational Research, Director of (Box 46, Folder 372)
  - Educational Resources and Services, Office of (Box 46, Folder 373)
  - Educational Resources and Services, Office of Educational television (Box 46, Folder 374)
  - Engineering, Appointment of Dr. George Sonneman as Professor (Box 46, Folder 375)
  - Engineering Building (Box 46, Folder 376)
  - Engineering Campaign (Box 46, Folder 377)
  - Engineering and Mines, School of, March 1962-July 1965 (Box 46, Folder 378-379)
  - Engineering and Mines, School of, August 1955-February 1962 (Box 47, Folder 380-386)
  - Engineering and Mines, School of, Faculty (Box 47, Folder 387)
  - Engineering and Mines, School of, Search for Dean (Box 48, Folder 388)
  - Engineering and Mines, School of, Board of Visitors (Box 48, Folder 389)
  - Engineering and Mines, School of, Holzman and Turkes, Optional Scheduling in Educational Institutions (Box 48, Folder 390)
  - English, Department of, 1955-1965 (Box 48, Folder 391-392)
  - English, Department of, Lee Case: Howard Committee, Correspondence (Box 48, Folder 393)
  - English, Department of, Lee Case: Howard Committee, Report (Box 48, Folder 394)
  - English, Department of, Edwin L. Peterson, Contemporary Composition Photos and transparencies (Box 48, Folder 395)
  - Environmental Health Program (Box 48, Folder 396)
  - Equal Education Opportunities Program (Box 48, Folder 397)
  - Extension Division (Box 49, Folder 398)
  - E General
    - Early - Education (Box 49, Folder 399)
    - Edwards - Ellenberger 6 Dwight D. Eisenhower Signatures (3 are initials only) 3 Milton Eisenhower Signatures (Box 49, Folder 400)
    - Elliott- Emerson (Box 49, Folder 401)
    - Emery - Epperson (Box 49, Folder 402)
    - Epstein - Everton (Box 49, Folder 403)
    - Ewald - Exerpta (Box 49, Folder 404)
  - Faculty (Box 49, Folder 405)
  - Faculty Committee on Merit Increases (Box 49, Folder 406)
  - Faculty Development Program (Box 49, Folder 407)
  - Faculty Housing (Box 50, Folder 408)
  - Faculty Letters (Box 50, Folder 409)
  - Faculty Meeting, Function of Faculty in University Policy, May 1958 (Box 50, Folder 410)
  - Faculty Person Program Review (Box 50, Folder 411)
  - Faculty Publication Committee (Box 50, Folder 412)
  - Faculty, Special Committee on Reimbursement for Faculty Travel (Box 50, Folder 413)
  - Faculty, Maurice Falk, Visiting Professor of Politics (Box 50, Folder 414)
  - Falk Clinic (Box 50, Folder 415)
  - Falk School (Box 50, Folder 416)